Hello friends, welcome to Tip Insights.
In today's video we will talk
about GIC i.e. General
Insurance Council.
Before making this video, I had
made a video on an empanelment.
In the same video, I received a comment
that Sir, you have also made a video on GIC.
A comment has already come
regarding this.  So many
people do not know about GIC.  That's why
today I have brought a video regarding this so that
you people can easily understand what GIC
is and how it processes.  This
is also a part of empanelment.  And further in
this video I am going to tell you in detail
how you
can apply for it.  What is its process
and which companies are involved in it?  That
means, if we apply for this, then
with which companies can our hospital tie up.
I am going to tell you all that in full detail.  So
video is very important.  So
you guys stay till the end of the video.  If you are new to the channel
then please subscribe to the channel.
Press the bell icon so that
you keep getting notifications of new videos.  So
let's start the video.
A few days ago you might have seen that
a scheme was launched by GIC named
Cashless Everywhere.  That means, at that time the General
Insurance Council had made an
announcement that you people, that is, those who are
health insurance policy holders, can
go to any hospital and
take a cashless claim.  Whether that hospital is on the
panel of that company or not.  This means that the
hospital has to provide treatment to that patient under Cashless Everywhere.  Be
it a
patient of HDFC Ergo or Care Health
or Neevapa.  So this
scheme was ingrained in him.  Along with that,
a scheme was also started regarding common empanelment, in
which
four insurance companies were added to it by applying online,
which were government insurance
companies. I will tell you the names of those companies. The
first company was National
Insurance Company Limited, the second was The New
India Insurance, the third was The Oriental
Insurance Company Limited and the fourth was
United India Insurance Company Limited.
So, the common empanelment which is going on under GIC, for which the
hospital has to apply online, then when you apply under it, that is,
suppose a new
hospital is opened and there is not a single panel in it, then the
biggest benefit for it is
that if it applies under GIC, that is,
applies for common empanelment, then when
you go there, then these four
companies which I have mentioned, National
Insurance, The New India Insurance, The
Oriental Insurance and United India
Insurance, then you will get empanelled with all the TPAs ​​associated with these companies.  That means there will be a
direct tie up with them.  Because the
work of these companies is being done by TPA.  That
means this is an insurance company.
It offers different types of insurance.
General General Insurance.  That means it
also works in health.  It does this in the motor also.
Many types of insurance are provided through this type.
So they have
hired separate TPAs ​​to get their work done.
TPS means getting the work done from third party.
Like Vidal TPA and there
are many other TPAs ​​whose names are also
written in it.  It became Medisist, it became MD
India, it became Paramount, it became Heritage
, it became FAPL i.e. Family Health
Plan Raksha, Goodal, I have already
told you.  It became Medse, it became Genesis
, it became Health India Insurance TPA
Services Pvt. Ltd., it became Good
Health.  So in this way
you will have direct
tie up with all the TPAs.  But those companies should be
government owned.  That means the
insurance companies will be government owned.
So in the common implementation, it will happen that there will be a
direct panel with all the TPs associated with the four companies, National Insurance, The New India Insurance, Oriental Insurance and United India.  If you
apply for this and fulfill their terms and conditions and
complete all their required documents, then
you will be directly connected with many TPAs ​​in the common empanelment.
Now you will talk about what happened to the remaining
companies?  So for them,
GIC had already launched a plan
which they were using as cashless everywhere plan.   That
means their aim is that through this common
empanelment, people from all TPAs ​​will be connected.  That is,
through the common empanelment of the hospital, all the TPAs, that is, the
names I told you, Jenny Vidal, Volo
Medsave and all the TPs of this type, will be
directly connected to them
through the common empanelment and after that, those who are left will have to give the
claim to the policy holders through Cashless Everywhere. The
names of those who are left are like
Bajaj, Chola Mandalam, Navi
General, Future General, HDFC,
If Toki, ICICI LBRD.
These are all private insurances.  Reliance was established.
These are all private insurance
companies.  If you have their card
then you will have to go inside the hospital and
tell them that I want to get treatment through this.
If that hospital
is not on your panel, that is, that hospital does not have a tie-up with that company,
then they will
submit your request to the insurance company through Cashless Everywhere and they will take
approval.  But the truth is
that under Cashless Everywhere, one has to inform 48 hours in advance.
Then his
treatment process begins.  So
many people submit it for approval.
Many people refuse.   The
hospital people are there and
even after submitting it many times, approval does not come.   The
insurance company stops it midway
giving some reason or the other.  So Cashless
Everywhere is
not working so smoothly.  This is being seen in most of the hospitals,
mostly within the state, mostly
within the district.  Many
people also comment on this.  So this
is its process.  Now I want to show you some cards
so that you people can understand
that if your hospital has joined the common empanelment, that is,
you have tied up with these companies, then
what type of people will
come with the cards and whether you can treat them with those cards
or not.
So by looking at these cards you
can decide whether I have been empanelled
or not.  So you will
understand easily by looking at it.  So
I am going to show it to you guys on the screen.   First of all
you have to go to Google and open a common
panel.  When you search through Search GIC,
I will provide you its link.
This type of page will
open in front of you.  After this
you will have to fill an information inside it.   There will be
different steps given in it.  For example, if a
hospital user clicks here and
continues here, then after coming here, these pages will keep
opening.  In which you will have to follow the first step
inside it.  Within that, the
general information will appear, in which the
name of the owner of the hospital, name of the hospital,
address, PAN number of the hospital, registration
number will appear. In the second step, the
provider information i.e.
Rohini ID of the hospital will appear, and what
type of facility the hospital has, whether it is a single facility
hospital or a multi-specialty hospital,
you will have to mention it in that form,
which will open in front of you online after clicking on it.  The
third step
in this is the infrastructure of the hospital.
That is, how many private rooms are there,
how many semi-private rooms are there, how many general
wards are there, is there an ICU or not?  All this will have to be
filled within its infrastructure.
After that, the next step will be about
staff and quality, that is, how much
staff do you have, how many doctors,
how many MBBS doctors, how many nurses
, how many surgeons, how many on-co doctors
?  And you have to fill in
all the details related to ambulance etc.
Whatever
hospital or doctor you have,
you have to fill in whatever details are asked in it.  The
next step is number five inside it.
In that, the contact details of the hospital are being asked, that is, the
email ID of the owner of the hospital or the email ID and contact number of the
TPA coordinator of the hospital,
you will have to provide all this in it.
After that, in the sixth step, you will have to
upload your documents to the hospital.  The
registration number of the hospital will be uploaded inside it.
Rohini has a certificate, that must be it.
Proprietorship certificate will also be there.  The owner
's documents will be uploaded in it.  Like
signature etc. is done, PAN card is done,
copy of cancelled cheque is done.  Fire NOC,
BMW Certificate and GST Certificate.  There are
some documents of this type.  You have to
scan these in advance and
upload them.  Along with this, you
also have to upload the hospital photos in the seventh step.
Like the front photo of the hospital,
back photo, ICU, OPD,
photos of all the beds of ICU etc.,
you have to upload everything in it.
And the eighth step, the final step,
you have to look at it.
Everything has to be checked thoroughly there.   The
documents have to be uploaded properly
and after that, you have to
submit it finally in the eighth step.  After final submission,
if your panel is made and
patients start coming to you, then the
first card that the patients who come to you will bring is this.
After common empanelment, when patients come to you, if they
bring this type of card, then first of all
you have to see on that card
which is the insurance company.  Now look up,
this is Ifcotoko's card.  Look here,
this is If Tokyo Insurance Company and here
is Paramount TP.  Ok?  So you
cannot take this.  You cannot take this patient
because the
name of any of those four companies is not written here.
Which four companies?  National Insurance, The
New India Insurance, The Oriental
Insurance and United India.  If the
name of any of the four is not there then
you cannot take this patient.  If the
name of any of those four was written here then
you could have taken it easily because they get
their work done through TPA,
Paramount.  So
you cannot take this patient.  If you want to take this patient, then
you can take this patient under the scheme of Cashless Everywhere.  Now the second
card I will show you will make you understand.
Look, I had told you about four companies, the
name of one of them has come here.
Look at this, United India Assurance
Company Limited, okay, this name has come in
front of you, its TP is Vidal
TPA, see it is written below, earlier it used to be
Vipul, now it has been converted to Vipul Vidal, so
this TP has come, if a patient
brings this type of card to you,
then you can give cashless claim to that patient
because you have common empanelment of this company,
so this card will be accepted with
you, you can give cashless claim to this patient,
now I will show you one more card,
see, this is the card of Park Mediclaim.
Ok?  Look at this Park Mediclaim
Park Medical is a TPA.  Ok?
Card was written on its back side.  Which of these
companies is this or National Insurance.  It is
not a little clear.  Rest of these four
companies are any of them which
you will understand if you see the card.  It is not coming out a little clear in this.
So
you can give cashless claim to this patient also because he will also
come in your panel.  Now let me
show you another card.  Look at this.  Look,
this is from Maxpa.  Max Bupa i.e. Niva
Bupa which has now become Max Bupa
is a private company.  This is working individually.
It has no TPA.  Look at what is
written here.  So, you
can give this patient cashless anywhere but
not cashless because the
name of any insurance company or TPA is
not mentioned on the card.  So only if you identify the card in this way,
you will be
able to give a proper cashless claim to the patient.  Otherwise, you will have to make
the claim by going cashless everywhere.  Let
me show you one more card.
Look at this,
this is also a private company.  Universal Somo
is a general insurance company.  Look at this also,
this is the name of the company here.  Even in this, the
name of none of those four is there.  Nor is there any
name of any TP.  So you
cannot give this cashless claim also.  You can also treat
this patient under Cashless Everywhere.
So
before admitting the patient, you have to check his card very carefully.  It has to be
verified.   Have to
confirm it.  Otherwise you
admitted the patient and later you said that
your card is not valid.  If it doesn't work
then that problem is going to happen.  After
watching this video, you must have understood the complete process of
how you have to do the common empanelment that is taking place inside GIC.
What will be its process and
within that you people have to keep in mind
which companies' panels you have.
Which companies do not have it and
you can apply only for those government companies
through GIC.  So
this video was very important.  So you
people have to share this video with everyone
so that people can understand and the
new hospitals that are opening can
connect their hospitals with these TPAs.  You can
tie up so that maximum number of
policy holders and
patients who come with their health cards can be
given the benefit of this thing.  So that's all for
today's video.  If you like the video, please
like the video.  Please subscribe to the channel.
Press the bell icon
so that you keep getting notifications of new videos.
So see you in the next video.
Goodbye until then.